<chapter id="sum.gui">
    <title>The BEAM Snow Radiance processor</title>

    <para>
        The BEAM Snow Radiance processor can be invoked from the Visat 'Tools' menu as shown below.
    </para>
    <figure id="figure.gui.visat.snowradiance">
        <title>The Snow Radiance processor in BEAM Visat</title>
        <graphic scale="40" fileref="figures/snowradiance_in_beam.png"/>
    </figure>

    <para>
        The GUI for the Snow Radiance processor consists of three tab panes
        <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
            <listitem>
                I/O Parameters
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                Target Bands
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                Processing Parameters
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        which will be described below.
    </para>

    <sect1 id="sum.gui.io">
        <title>I/O Parameters</title>
        <para>
            The Snow Radiance processor needs as input a MERIS and an (A)ATSR L1b product to derive all the quantities
            listed in the previous chapter. For the derival of only snow grain size, snow albedo and soot content,
            an (A)ATSR L1b product is not required.
        </para>

        <sect2 id="sum.gui.io.io">
            <title>I/O Parameters Tab Pane</title>

            <figure id="figure.gui.io.iotab">
                <title>Snow Radiance processor: I/O Parameters Tab Pane</title>
                <graphic scale="60" fileref="figures/iotab.png"/>
            </figure>

            This tab pane consists of the following components:
            <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
                <listitem>
                    MERIS source product file: Select the source product file by either typing the product path into the
                    text
                    filed or by pressing the file selection button to invoke a standard file dialog.
                    This source product must be a standard MERIS L1b product.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    Checkbox 'Compute snow grain size / pollution only (no AATSR L1b required)':
                    If this checkbox is selected, only snow grain size, snow albedo and soot content will be computed.
                    The text field to select an AATSR L1b product (see below) will be hidden
                    (<xref linkend="figure.gui.io.iotabmerisonly" xrefstyle="select: label"/>).
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    AATSR source product file: Select the source product file by either typing the product path into the
                    text
                    filed or by pressing the file selection button to invoke a standard file dialog.
                    This source product must be a standard AATSR L1b product.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    Target product file: Select the target product file by either typing the product path into the text
                    filed or by pressing the file selection button to invoke a standard file dialog.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    Target product format and target directory:
                    <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
                        <listitem>
                            'Save as': If this checkbox is selected, the output product will be saved to disk.
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            Target product format: Select one of the available output product formats.
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            Select the target product directory by either typing the product path into the text
                            filed or by pressing the file selection button to invoke a standard file dialog.
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    'Open in Visat': If this checkbox is selected, the output product is opened in Visat
                    after successful processing.
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>

            <figure id="figure.gui.io.iotabmerisonly">
                <title>Snow Radiance processor: I/O Parameters Tab Pane in case no AATSR product shall be used</title>
                <graphic scale="60" fileref="figures/iotab_merisonly.png"/>
            </figure>

        </sect2>

        <sect2 id="sum.gui.io.control">
            <title>Control Buttons</title>

            From the 'I/O Parameters' tab pane, the following control buttons can be accessed:
            <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
                <listitem>
                    'Run': If this button is clicked, the processor will start the computations.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    'Close': If this button is clicked, the 'MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy Toolbox' dialog is closed.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    'Help': If this button is clicked, this manual is displayed as online help.
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>

            <figure id="figure.gui.io.controlbuttons">
                <title>Synergy Toolbox: control buttons</title>
                <graphic scale="60" fileref="figures/controlbuttons.png"/>
            </figure>

        </sect2>

    </sect1>


    <sect1 id="sum.gui.targetbands">
        <title>Target Bands</title>

        <para>
            The user interface for the quantities to be computed and written to the target product consists of two
            lists of check boxes (<xref linkend="figure.targetbands.default" xrefstyle="select: label"/>):
            <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
                <listitem>
                    Snow properties
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    Complementary quantities
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>

            <figure id="figure.targetbands.default">
                <title>Snow Radiance processor: Target Bands Tab Pane</title>
                <graphic scale="60" fileref="figures/targetbandstab.png"/>
            </figure>
        </para>

        <para>
            The snow properties which can be selected are:
            <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
                <listitem>
                    'Compute snow grain size': If this checkbox is selected, the snow grain size will be computed
                    and written as single band to the target product.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    'Compute snow albedo': If this checkbox is selected, the snow albedo will be computed
                    and written as single band to the target product.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    'Compute snow soot content': If this checkbox is selected, the snow soot content will be computed
                    and written as single band to the target product.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    'Compute emissivity': If this checkbox is selected, the emissivity will be computed
                    and written as single band to the target product. This option is enabled only if both MERIS and AATSR
                    products were given as inputs.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    'Compute temperature': If this checkbox is selected, the snow temperature will be computed
                    and written as single band to the target product. This option is enabled only if both MERIS and AATSR
                    products were given as inputs.
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>

        <para>
            The complementary quantities which can be selected are:
            <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
                <listitem>
                    'Water vapour (from MERIS)': If this checkbox is selected, the water vapour derived from the
                    MERIS product will be written as single band to the target product.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    'NDVI (from MERIS)': If this checkbox is selected, the NDVI derived from the
                    MERIS product will be written as single band to the target product.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    'NDSI (from AATSR)': If this checkbox is selected, the NDSI derived from the
                    AATSR product will be written as single band to the target product.
                    This option is enabled only if both MERIS and AATSR
                    products were given as inputs.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    'MDSI (from MERIS)': If this checkbox is selected, the MDSI derived from the
                    MERIS product will be written as single band to the target product.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    'AATSR L1 flags': If this checkbox is selected, the AATSR L1 flags taken from the
                    AATSR product will be written as single band to the target product.
                    This option is enabled only if both MERIS and AATSR
                    products were given as inputs.
                </listitem>

            </itemizedlist>
        </para>

    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="sum.gui.processing">
        <title>Processing Parameters</title>

        TODO!!!

        <para>
            The Processor for Aerosol Retrieval and Atmospheric Correction is the third of three main modules
            within the MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy toolbox.
            Its purpose is to derive aerosol optical depths over land and/or ocean and (optionally) provide an
            atmospheric correction by using the derived AODs. The processor also makes use of quantities
            derived from the cloud screening module. Therefore, the input for the aerosol retrieval must be
            an output product from the cloud screening.
        </para>

         <para>
            The user interface for the Aerosol Retrieval and Atmospheric Correction
             can be accessed by clicking the 'Aerosol Retrieval and Atmospheric Correction'
            tab in the 'MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy Toolbox' dialog.
            (<xref linkend="figure.toolbox.aerosol" xrefstyle="select: label"/>):

            <figure id="figure.toolbox.aerosol">
                <title>Synergy Toolbox: Aerosol Retrieval and Atmospheric Correction Tab Pane</title>
                <graphic scale="60" fileref="figures/aerosolretrievaltab.png"/>
            </figure>
        </para>

        <para>
            The Aerosol Retrieval and Atmospheric Correction tab pane consists of the following components:
            <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
                <listitem>
                    'Retrieve AODs over ocean': If this checkbox is selected, aerosol optical depths will
                    be retrieved over ocean. The default is 'true'.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    'Retrieve AODs over land': If this checkbox is selected, aerosol optical depths will
                    be retrieved over land. The default is 'true'.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        'Retrieve surface directional reflectances over land (time consuming!)':
                        If this checkbox is selected,
                        SDRs will be retrieved from rescaled AODs. This computation is performed over land only.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                       Due to the nature of the algorithm, the retrieval of surface directional
                       reflectances requires much more computation time than the pure aerosol retrieval.
                       If you are interested in aerosol quantities only, it is recommended to keep
                       this option unselected. For the computation of surface directional reflectances
                       on larger datasets, it is further recommended to create in advance subsets of
                       the input data which just cover the regions of interest.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                 <listitem>
                    'N x N average for AOD retrieval': Text field to set
                    the number of pixels to average over in the aerosol retrieval. The default number is '7',
                    which corresponds to a square with 3 pixels to each side of a center pixel.
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                    'Soil surface reflectance spectrum': Text field to set the filename containing
                    the soil surface reflectance spectrum. The default is 'spec_soil.dat',
                    this file is included in the auxiliary data
                    (see <xref linkend="sum.installation.auxdata" xrefstyle="select: label"/>)
                    If the user wants to use a different file, it must be selected via the
                    file chooser button right to the test field. Note that any user selected file
                    must exactly follow the format of the default file.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    'Vegetation surface reflectance spectrum': Text field to set the filename containing
                    the vegetation surface reflectance spectrum. The default is 'veg_soil.dat',
                    this file is included in the auxiliary data
                    (see<xref linkend="sum.installation.auxdata" xrefstyle="select: label"/>)
                    If the user wants to use a different file, it must be selected via the
                    file chooser button right to the test field. Note that any user selected file
                    must exactly follow the format of the default file.
                </listitem>

                 <listitem>
                     <para>
                         'Use default land aerosol models (recommended)': If this radio button is selected,
                         the default land aerosol models are used for aerosol retrieval. This set of
                         models is included in the 'standard' auxiliary data set
                         (see<xref linkend="sum.installation.auxdata" xrefstyle="select: label"/>).
                         No further user action is required. This option is recommended not only for
                         simplicity, but also because only a small number of models is used.
                         For most purposes, this option will be sufficient.
                         A large number of models (which can be specified with the option below)
                         significantly increases computation time for the aerosol retrieval.
                     </para>
                     <para>
                         For more details on these aerosol models and underlying lookup tables see [3] and [6].
                     </para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        'Use specific land aerosol models (for advanced users)': If this radio button is selected,
                        specific land aerosol models must be entered by a comma-separated list of model indices
                        in the text field below.
                        To use this option for aerosol retrieval,
                        the 'full' auxiliary data set
                        (see<xref linkend="sum.installation.auxdata" xrefstyle="select: label"/>)
                        must be downloaded and installed.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        For more details on these aerosol models and underlying lookup tables see [3] and [6].
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        'List of land aerosol models': Text field to set a comma separated list of the indices of
                        the aerosol models to be used for the land aerosol retrieval
                        (<xref linkend="figure.toolbox.aerosol.custommodels" xrefstyle="select: label"/>).
                        This text field is enabled only if the 'Use specific land aerosol models (for advanced users)'
                        radio button is selected.
                        The valid range of indices is [1,40].
                        In principle, up to all 40 models could be entered. However,
                        to keep computation time in an acceptable frame, it is recommended to use as few
                        models as possible.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        For more details on these aerosol models and underlying lookup tables see [3] and [6].
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>

        <figure id="figure.toolbox.aerosol.custommodels">
            <title>Synergy Toolbox: Selection of aerosol models for land aerosol retrieval</title>
            <graphic scale="60" fileref="figures/customLandAerosolModels.png"/>
        </figure>
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="sum.toolbox.commandline">
        <title>Processing from command line</title>
        Since the MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy toolbox makes use of the BEAM graph processing framework, it can be
        used also as a command line tool outside BEAM-VISAT. The graph processing is invoked
        by the command
        <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
            <listitem>
                ${BEAM-INSTALL-DIR}/bin/gpt
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        To obtain general help on the graph processing, use the command
        <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
            <listitem>
                ${BEAM-INSTALL-DIR}/bin/gpt -h
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        Specific help on the MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy toolbox can be obtained with
        <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
            <listitem>
                ${BEAM-INSTALL-DIR}/bin/gpt -h synergy.Master
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        In this case, information on the usage and a list of all available parameters are given
        (see <xref linkend="figure.toolbox.gpt" xrefstyle="select: label"/>).


        <figure id="figure.toolbox.gpt">
            <title>'Synergy Toolbox: command line processing</title>
            <graphic scale="40" fileref="figures/synergy_gpt.png"/>
        </figure>

    </sect1>

</chapter>
